Marty Gormley

martinjosephgormley@gmail.com martygormley.com github.com/martyjg linkedin.com/in/martygormley

Profile

My drive for web development derives from my enjoyment of problem-solving, the opportunity of learning how to tackle these problems from different perspectives and the satisfaction of making quality products. I'm searching for a position where I can work and learn creatively in a progressive and modern team.

Skills

Proficient
with...
HTML5, CSS,
JavaScript (ES6,
Typescript),
React, Node,
Hapi, Angular,
LESS, SASS, Git,
Gulp

Experience with...

Express, Jasmine, Ruby, PHP, behat, Wordpress, Jenkins, Docker, MySQL Currently playing with...

Unity, Processing, React Native, Firebase

Experience

Bureau for Visual Affairs - Front End Web Developer

February 2017 - present

At the BfVA (Bureau for Visual affairs), I work across a range of projects for clients from the cultural, scientific and commercial sectors. I have gained strong experience in working with the React library (isomorphically) and have moved to writing CSS using BAS library and maintaining our own CSS repository. I also gained experience in creating a custom user-friendly CMS according to our clients' wishes in Wordpress. In my time at BfVA I learned to work in tight sprints, and the necessity of being aware of my own timespans and those of my colleagues (other devs, designers, clients). I was fortunate to have this position in a small team where development is fluid and allows for peer-review, pair-programming and discussion about UX when needed.

The Mill - Front End Web Developer

April 2016 - February 2017

Going full-time with The Mill meant I was given my own front-end project to work on, alongside assisting the team's lead Front End Dev with another SPA project. Across these projects I've gained experience with testing, CSS preprocessors, continuous deployment and virtual machines.

The Mill – Web Developer/Designer Intern February 2016 – April 2016

My internship at The Mill gave me a taste of every position in a development team and introduced me to real experience in an agile development process. Working closely with the team's designer helped develop my UX design skills and has aided me greatly in discussing a product's planning.

Unicorns In Tech - Events and Community Manager

October 2014 - June 2015

Organising the Unicorns In Tech community gave me experience of working alone and in a team to see a large project through from start to completion. Arranging speakers and seeking new members provided me with an insight into the tech and startup world.

Education

General Assembly - Web Development Immersive

August 2015 - January 2016

The projects I completed during the course allowed me to experience the process of conceptualisation, planning, development and deployment. The course has given me experience of an agile process and git/github. Most importantly, WDI has given me the tools to teach myself any new technology with confidence.

Goldsmiths College (UoL) – BSc Psychology September 2011 – July 2014

Lumen Christi College - A*AAB at A-Level September 2009 - June 2011

Interests

Outside of programming, I like music, film, video games and hanging out. For weekend fun I'm always on the lookout for new cafes, bars and parties so please send any tips my way. I also occasionally mentor at Codebar, a web development learning initiative for underrepresented groups.